What's up pumpers? This is the 3rd video of the history of the Pump
¿Qué onda pumpers? Este es el video 3 de la historia de la Pump
If you do not remember the previous 2, here they are
Si no recuerdan los 2 anteriores quí los dejo.
in case you remember we stayed in The Prex,
si  recuerdan no quedamos en la Prex,
which  was the union between Premiere and Extra versions
que fue la union de la Premiere y la Extra
Well, On May 2012 the Pump it up The Rebirth was released
bueno, ya para mayo del 2012 ve la luz  la Pump it up The Rebirth
The 8th dance floor, where Division mode was introduced
The 8th dance floor, donde se introdujo el modo División
In Division mode you had to choose letters
En el modo división tenías que elegir letras
to choose the difficulty; Gs (Groove) or Ws (Wild)
para escoger la dificultad; Gs (Groove) o Ws (Wild)
For  "Groove" mode You had to pick the letter G
Para modo "Groove" tenias que escoger la letra G
It was a relaxed mode with jumps
era un modo hard relajado y con saltos
If you pressed only Ws the chart will changed to a difficulty even harder than crazy
Si presionabas solamente Ws cambiabas a un modo inclusio más difícill incluso  que el crazy
In a nutshell, this mode allowed you to change the difficulty in the middle of the song.
en pocas palabras este modo te permitía cambiar la dificultad en medio de la canción.
This mode was quite original what a shame  they didn't keep it!...
Éste modo fue bastante original ¡qué lástima que no siguieron con él!...
In addition to this mode, "half double" was introduced
En adición a este modo también se presentó el "half double" el cual consistía
which consisted on playing in the middle with the 6 arrows where the two dance floors join.
en jugar en la flechas del medio las 6 flechas que unen los dos tapetes.
In fact, so far the most difficult patterns to understand are in Half double segments.
De hecho, hasta la fecha los patrones más difíciles de entender son los de Half double
(in the middle).
es decir los de en medio.
This machine featured 36 new songs and any old
Ésta máquina contó con 36 canciones nuevas y ninguna vieja
hence the name "rebirth" (The Rebirth).
por eso el nombre "el renacimiento" (The Rebirth).
DR. M, Love is a danger zone, Zzanga,
Resaltaron: DR. M, Love is a danger zone, Zzanga,
Csikospost, Winter, baby Swing outstanded
Csikospost, Winter, Swing baby
and the hardest Will O the Wisp and Vook
y las más difíciles Will O the wisp y Vook
in single and double, respectively.
en single y doble respectivamente.
Then came the Premiere 2, It had the 36 Rebirth songs
Después salió la Premiere 2, que fueron las 36 canciones de la Rebirth
plus 66 more from the Premiere.
más otras 66 viejas de la Premiere.
The new feature here was the inclusion of speed 3 (x3)
Lo novedoso aquí fue la inclusión de la velocidad 3 (x3)
which made easier the reading of many steps
lo cual facilitó la lectura de muchos pasos
since many songs were slow by x2 but  fast x3
pues muchas canciones eran lentas por dos y rápidas por cuatro
Can can was a clear example.
como por ejemplo Can can.
We later wlecomed Prex 2 where 21 songs Extra were added
Después damos pasos a la Prex 2  cual agregó 21 canciones de la Extra
so they're only compilations.
por lo que son sólo compilaciones.
As early as May 2003 the Premiere 3 came out featuring Latin American pop songs
Ya para mayo del 2003 sale la Premiere 3 con canciones de American y Latin pop
It was created by Andamiro especially for Latin America
fue creada por Andamiro especialmente para Latinoamérica
where the game had already gained enough popularity
donde el juego ya había ganado bastante popularidad
especially in Mexico where it was a hit.
especialmente en México donde era toda una sensación.
Here they returned the Half-double, which was no longer in an earlier version.
Aquí regresaron el Half-double, el cual ya no estaba en una versión anterior.
The most popular tracks of this album were: Bee, Conga,
Los tracks más populares de este disco fueron: Bee, Conga,
Join the party, Mexi Mexi, although the most complicated were
Join the party, Mexi Mexi,  aunque los  más complicados fueron
DJ. Nightmare and Beat of the War of Banya.
DJ. Nightmare y Beat of the war de Banya.
So we give way to 3 where Prex nightmare mode was introduced
Así damos paso a la Prex 3 donde surgió el nightmare
since the pumpers were eager to have more difficult charts.
ya que los pumpers estaban sedientos de dificultad.
Unlike "Extra expert" steps for double on the Extra version
Al contrario de los pasos del doble experto de la Extra
the charts quality  was clearly superior with better arrow sequences.
la calidad de los charts fue claramente superior y con mejores secuencias de flechas
Andamiro really wanted to have licenses popular hits in the West
Andamiro quería tener licencias de éxitos realmente populares en occidente
such as Objection by Shakira (Te aviso te anuncio in Spanish)
como Objection de Shakira (Te aviso te anuncio en español),
It's my party by Thalia (Arrasando in Spanish) and Just a Girl by No Doubt
It's my party de Thalia (Arrasando en español) y Just a girl de No doubt
In addition to Music by Madonna and we can't forget  Master of Puppets by Metallica
además the Music y no podemos olvidar Master of puppets de Metallica
but apparently they couldn't buy them or their preices were too high to afford
pero al parecer no logró comprarlas o no les llegó al precio y las tuvo que
so Andamiro hat to remove them from the list of available songs but they remained hidden on the disc.
eliminar de la lista disponible no haciéndolo así del disco.
Only Come to me  by Banya, Empire of the Sun by Novasonic
Solo quedaron: Come to me de Banya, Empire of the sun de Novasonic
and Let's get the party started by Pink remained.
y Let's get the party satarted  de Pink
This last song was undoubtedly an icon of difficulty in those days
esta última canción fue sin lugar a dudas un ícono de dificultad en esos tiempos
and plus the introduction nightmare mode
y aunado a la introducción del modo nightmare
the difficulty of the game was exponentially increased
aumentó exponencialmente la dificultad del juego.
It is worth mentioning that some charts were redesigned using now long notes
Cabe mencionar que algunos pasos fueron cambiados usando ahora notas largas para
increasing that way the difficulty. That's the case of Join the party.
aumentar su dificultad. Es el caso de Join the party.
As some of you may know
Como algunos de ustedes sabrán
relesing a PC version of the game was a big mistake that represented huge
sacar una versión para PC fue un gran error que representó grandes
monetary loss to Andamiro because pirated copies were soon on the market
pérdidas para Andamiro ya que las copias piratas no se hicieron esperar
many people began to modify discs generating a wave of piracy.
muchas personas empezaron a modificar los discos generando así una ola de piratería.
This video comes to an end, don't forget to share it, hit that like button
Hasta aquí llega este vídeo, no olviden compartirlo, darle like
I'm Oscar Jark and I see you in the nex one.
soy Oscar Jark y nos vemos en la siguiente
CYA!.
CYA!